Preliminary Guide to the Henry Weitz Papers, 1931 - 1978
Duke University. University Archives
Henry Weitz papers 1931 - 1978
Weitz, Henry
16.5 linear feet, Extent: 16000 Items
Duke University. University Archives
Henry Weitz, a psychologist and professor of education, was director of Duke University's Bureau of Testing and Guidance (later the University Counseling Center) from 1950 to 1978. The Henry Weitz Papers include correspondence, reports, minutes, writings, speeches, publications, research and testing materials, course materials, and other documents related to Weitz's career at the University of Delaware and Duke University. Most of the materials are related to Weitz's interest in guidance, vocational, and adjustment counseling for students. English.
UA.29.02.0053
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Unprocessed materials are closed pending processing.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Henry Weitz Papers was received by the University Archives as a gift in 1980, 1981, and 1995.
Biographical Note
Henry Weitz was born in New York in 1911. He received a bachelor's degree from Dartmouth College and a master's degree and doctorate in education from Rutgers University. Prior to coming to Duke, Weitz was the director of the Psychological Services Center at the University of Delaware, served as a psychologist and instructor in the U.S. Army, and was a teacher and guidance counsellor for the Rahway, New Jersey, public schools.
Weitz arrived at Duke University in 1950. He served as an associate professor of education and director of the University Counseling Center (formerly the Bureau of Testing and Guidance). He was a member of the American Psychological Association, the American Statistical Association, the North Carolina Vocational Guidance Association, and a number of other societies. Weitz retired in 1978.
Collection Overview
The Henry Weitz Papers include correspondence, reports, minutes, writings, speeches, publications, research and testing materials, course materials, and other documents related to Weitz's career at the University of Delaware and Duke University. Most of the materials are related to Weitz's interest in guidance, vocational, and adjustment counseling for students.
Subject Headings
Career education; Duke University. Bureau of Testing and Guidance; Duke University -- Faculty; Duke University. University Counseling Center; Educational counseling; Student adjustment; University of Delaware. Psychological Services Center; Vocational guidance; Weitz, Henry
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  The Henry Weitz papers are only preliminarily processed. The lists of materials within each box represent major subjects, but they are not folder lists.
  - Dartmouth Literary Magazine, May 1931 (Box 1)
  - Guidance as Behavior Change, 1961-1963, (5 drafts) (Box 1)
  - Publications (Box 1)
  - Writings (Box 2)
  - Reprints (Box 2)
  - Speeches (Box 2)
  - Junior Science Symposium files (Box 2)
  - Research Tests and Correspondence (Box 2)
  - A Draft Proposal for a Comprehensive Testing Program for the Durham High School, consultant Henry Weitz, 1952 (Box 3)
  - "Testing Procedures and Norms" binder (Box 3)
  - Bureau of Testing and Guidance, Duke University, Annual Report
    - 1944-1945 (Box 3)
    - 1950-1959, in binder (Box 3)
    - 1960-1969, in binder (Box 3)
  - "Writing and Research" binder (Box 3)
  - "Academic Orientation" course binder (Box 3)
  - "DHEW Social Security Admin., Bureau of Hearings and Appeals" binder (Box 3)
  - "Test Manuals"
    - "Intelligence, Scholastic Aptitude, and Personality" binder (Box 3)
    - "Special Abilities" binder (Box 3)
    - "Achievement and Interest" binder (Box 3)
  - Binder of teaching materials (Box 3)
  - Political Science Measurement Project (Box 3)
  - Binder of teaching materials (Box 3)
  - An Interpretive Manual for the Duke University Placement Testing Program (Box 3)
  - Education Department Committee files (Box 4)
  - University Graduate Program Committee files (Box 4)
  - Non-University Counseling, Reports, Education files (Box 4)
  - Speech (Box 4)
  - Writings (Box 4)
  - Lecture notes (Box 4)
  - Lecture Notes (Box 5)
  - Exams and Quizzes (Box 5)
  - Course Materials (Box 5)
  - Manuals for Practicum in Counseling (Box 5)
  - Mental Measurements Yearbook reviews (Box 5)
  - "Higher Education" research file (Box 5)
  - NC Dept. of Public Instruction, Counseling Education and Certification (Box 5)
  - Honors-Masters Program files (Box 5)
  - Political Science Test binder (Box 6)
  - Appointments and budgets, Bureau of Testing and Guidance files (Box 6)
  - Correspondence (Box 6)
  - Counselor Training and Certification files (Box 6)
  - Testing files (Box 6)
  - AOP files (Box 6)
  - Improving the Academic Adjustment of College Freshmen progress report, February 1, 1962 (Box 6)
  - Research files (Box 6)
  - Writings (Box 6)
  - Writings (Box 7)
  - Speeches (Box 7)
  - Research files (Box 7)
  - Testing files (Box 7)
  - Reprints (Box 7)
  - Reserve Corps records, 1947-1953 (Box 8)
  - University of Delaware files (Box 8)
  - Duke University Newcomers file (Box 8)
  - Professional and personal correspondence (Box 8)
  - Newspaper reports and clippings (Box 8)
  - Lecture notes (Box 8)
  - Education file (Box 8)
  - Henry Weitz's dissertation (Box 8)
  - Ceylon files (Box 8)
  - Biarritz files (Box 8)
  - Lecture notes (Box 9)
  - Alphabetical subject files: correspondence, minutes, reports (Box 9)
  - Behavior Change Through Guidance files (Box 9)
  - Honors-Masters Program files (Box 10)
  - General Ins. files: tests, conference, course evaluation forms (Box 10)
  - Course Materials (Box 10)
  - Correspondence (Box 10)
  - Consultation files (Box 11)
  - Sabbatical files (Box 11)
  - Committee files (Box 11)
  - Publications (Box 11)
  - Certificates (Box 11)
  - Research project (Box 11)
  - Education Department Committee files (Box 11)